studytonight.com 2019-04-18

# Studytonight's Privacy Policy

## For Studytonight.com Website & Android App

* * *

At **Studytonight - Best place to Learn Coding Online** , accessible on [studytonight.com](https://www.studytonight.com/) and **Studytonight - Free Computer Programming Tutorials** android app, one of our main priorities is the privacy of our visitors. This Privacy Policy document contains types of information that is collected and recorded by Studytonight's website and android app, and how we use it.

If you have additional questions or require more information about our Privacy Policy, do not hesitate to contact us through email at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#03746643707776677a776c6d6a646b772d606c6e)

### Information Collection and Use

#### User Information

When a user registers for Studytonight's website using the link **https://www.studytonight.com/register** , he or she is asked to provide their email address and choose a password which are saved in our database. Studytonight, under no circumstance, shares the user information with any 3rd party application for monetary gains. The data is safely stored in our databases and we perform to the best of our abilities to safeguard the data from any digital theft.

Studytonight use **Sendgrid Email Service** to send promotional email newsletter to its registered users from which users can opt out if they want.

Studytonight's Android App utilises **Firebase** for sending push notifications to our Android App users using **OneSignal** services. OneSignal service stores general information about your device on which the application is installed for analytics purpose which is accessible to us.

Studytonight may provide its user's personal information to the applicable Application Partner(as specified above). The Application Partner's use of your personal information is subject to the Application Partner's separate privacy policy – and not this Privacy Statement. The URL to Application Partner's privacy policies are specified in "Third Party Privacy Policies" section below.

#### Log Files

Studytonight follows a standard procedure of using log files. These files log visitors when they visit websites. All hosting companies do this and a part of hosting services' analytics. The information collected by log files include internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, Internet Service Provider (ISP), date and time stamp, referring/exit pages, and possibly the number of clicks. These are not linked to any information that is personally identifiable. The purpose of the information is for analyzing trends, administering the site, tracking users' movement on the website, and gathering demographic information.

#### Cookies and Web Beacons

Like any other website, Studytonight uses 'cookies'. These cookies are used to store information including visitors' preferences, and the pages on the website that the visitor accessed or visited. The information is used to optimize the users' experience by customizing our web page content based on visitors' browser type and/or other information.

#### Google DoubleClick DART Cookie

Google is one of a third-party vendor on our site. It also uses cookies, known as DART cookies, to serve ads to our site visitors based upon their visit to www.website.com and other sites on the internet. However, visitors may choose to decline the use of DART cookies by visiting the Google ad and content network Privacy Policy at the following URL – <https://policies.google.com/technologies/ads>

### Third Party Privacy Policies

You may consult this list to find the Privacy Policy for each of the advertising partners of Studytonight.

Third-party ad servers or ad networks uses technologies like cookies, JavaScript, or Web Beacons that are used in their respective advertisements and links that appear on Studytonight's website, which are sent directly to users' browser. They automatically receive your IP address when this occurs. These technologies are used to measure the effectiveness of their advertising campaigns and/or to personalize the advertising content that you see on websites that you visit.

Note that Studytonight has no access to or control over these cookies that are used by third-party advertisers.

Studytonight's Privacy Policy does not apply to other advertisers or websites. Thus, we are advising you to consult the respective Privacy Policies of these third-party ad servers for more detailed information. It may include their practices and instructions about how to opt-out of certain options. You may find a complete list of these Privacy Policies and their links here:

You can choose to disable cookies through your individual browser options. To know more detailed information about cookie management with specific web browsers, it can be found at the browsers' respective websites.

### Communications

We may use your personal information to contact you in form of weekly/monthly newsletters, marketing or promotional materials.

### Links to Other Sites

Studytonight's website or Android App may contain links to other sites. If you click on a third-party link, you will be directed to that site. Note that these external sites are not operated by us. Therefore, we strongly advise you to review the Privacy Policy of these websites. We have no control over and assume no responsibility for the content, privacy policies, or practices of any third-party sites or services.

### Children's Information

Another part of our priority is adding protection for children while using the internet. We encourage parents and guardians to observe, participate in, and/or monitor and guide their online activity.

Studytonight does not knowingly collect any Personal Identifiable Information from children under the age of 13. If you think that your child provided this kind of information on our website, we strongly encourage you to contact us immediately and we will do our best efforts to promptly remove such information from our records.

### For EU and EEA Users in Compliance with GDPR

#### Web Traffic Analytics

We use Google Analytics application on our website for the following purpose:

  * To monitor website traffic and behaviour flows of users.
  * To analyze the effectiveness of online website features by observing the usage patterns etc.

#### Advertising

We display non-personalized ads to our EEA users. Non-Personalized ads will use only contextual information, including coarse general (city-level) location, and content on the current site or app; targeting is not based on the profile information or past behavior of a user.

Although these ads don't use cookies for ads personalization, they do use cookies to allow for frequency capping, aggregated ad reporting, and to combat fraud and abuse.

#### Mobile Application

We do not display any ads on our mobile app, hence we do not store or process any user data to target or profile our users without their consent.

We use OneSignal for sending push notifications to our mobile app users, for which OneSignal stores general information about the device on which the mobile application is installed.

OneSignal is thrid party application and its privacy policy can be accessed on its website (Link mentioned in the "Third Party Privacy Policies" section above.)

#### Online Privacy Policy Only

This privacy policy applies only to our online activities and is valid for visitors to our website and our mobile application users, regarding information shared and/or collected there.

This policy does not apply to any information collected offline or via channels other than our website and mobile application.

This Privacy policy was last updated on: Monday, October 15th, 2018
